# **DIANA KAGOTHO**

## Toronto, M5V 2V6

Phone: 647.877.7971 | Email: dianakago2@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/diana-kagotho | GitHub: https://github.com/dkagotho| Portfolio: https://diana-kagotho-portfolio.herokuapp.com

## Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer with industry experience building websites and web applications. I have experience working with JavaScript, Typescript, Node.js, SASS, Elixir, React, Bootstrap, YARN, MVC, ORM, MERN Stack, JSON, Firebase, BEM, Elixir and Git among others. With my unique blend of communications skills, technical capabilities and leadership experience, I believe I would make an invaluable member of your project and team.

#### **Technical Skills**

Front-End: HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, Typescript, BEM, Node.js.

**Back End:** Elixir, Typescript, MySQL, Curveball, Node.is, REST API.

**Source Control:** Git(Git Low), Github, Jira, Azure DevOps.

FrameWorks: React, Bootstrap, Material UI.

**UI/UX:** Wireframing.

#### **PROJECTS**

Facebook messenger clone| https://facebook-messenger-clone-bce12.firebaseapp.com | https://github.com/dkagotho/facebook-messenger-clone

Facebook messenger clone app.

Technology used include HTML, CSS, React, Node. js, Firebase, JavaScript, BEM.

## Netflix Clone| netflix-clone-e8561.firebaseapp.com | https://github.com/dkagotho/Netflix-clone

This is a simple Netflix clone that shows the trending movies, top rated movies, action movies, comedy movies, horror movies, romance movies and ducumentaries. The app also shows some trailers that have been grabbed from youtube. Technology used include HTML,CSS,React,Node.js,Firebase,JavaScript,BEM.

## Amazon Clone | https://clone-b1a9e.firebaseapp.com | https://github.com/dkagotho/Amazon-clone

This is a simple Amazon. It has user authentication and users are able to create accounts, log in and add items to cart. Technology used include HTML,CSS,React,Node.js,Firebase,JavaScript,BEM,Firebase authentication, react context API, react router.

#### Work Experience

# Web Developer, MIHOK SYSTEMS INC.

September 2021 - Current

- Writing well-designed, testable, efficient code by using web development best practices.
- Building and maintaining websites. Customizing websites according to objectives or user feedback.
- Plan, design, write, modify, integrate and test Web-site related code.
- Conduct tests and perform security and quality controls.
- Participating in the development and taking accountability for deliverables.
- Analyzing and writing programming code structures based on user requirements.
- Develop Website architecture and determine hardware and software requirements.
- Maintaining, expanding, and scaling our site.
- Staying plugged into emerging technologies and industry trends and applying them to operations and activities.
- Gathering information from clients about system functionality.

#### Web Developer Intern, MIHOK SYSTEMS INC.

April 2021 - September 2021

- Assisting the Development Manager with all aspects of software design and coding.
- Attending and contributing to company development meetings.
- Learning the codebase and improving my coding skills.
- Writing and maintaining code.
- Working on bug fixes.
- Responding to requests from the development team.
- Gathering information from clients about system functionality.

## Full Stack Developer Intern, MyShoperon

November 2020 - December 2020

- Developing back and front end website architecture using React and JavaScript.
- Designing user interactions on web pages.
- Developing back end website applications.
- Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring responsiveness of applications.
- Working alongside UI/UX designers for web design features.
- Seeing through a project from conception to finished product.
- Designing and developing APIs.
- Meeting both technical and consumer needs.
- Staying abreast of developments in web applications and programming languages.

# **Quality Assurance Analyst, Kev Group**

April 2020 - March 2021

- Work with developers to meet requirements and quality.
- Write, execute and maintain test cases.
- Participate in product design meetings.
- Collaborate with other QA analysts, BA analysts, UX designers, and product owners to ensure the best outcomes and experience for customers and users.
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on business and technical needs.
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and apply them into testing and processes as appropriate.

#### **Education & Certifications**

## **Full Stack Development Bootcamp Certificate**

University of Toronto school of continuing studies

January 2020 – July 2020

# **Cisco IT Essentials Certification**

May 2018 - August 2018

Junior IT Analyst Program
NPower Canada | Toronto

## **Customer Service Excellence Certificate**

**April 2018** 

August 2018

Ontario Tourism Education Corporation (OTEC)

## Masters of Arts in International Relations (partial completion)

September 2015-April 2017

United States International University- Africa

## **Bachelor of Arts Degree in Communication**

January 2009-October 2012

St. Paul's University, Limuru, Kenya